I'm talking to you about
سأتحدث لكم اليوم
the worst form of human rights violation,
عن أسوأ شكل لإنتهاكات الحقوق الإنسانية
the third-largest organized crime,
عن ثالث أكبر جريمة منظمة
a $10 billion industry.
عن صناعة تساوي 10 مليارات من الدولار
I'm talking to you about modern-day slavery.
إنها عبودية العصر الحديث
I'd like to tell you the story
أرغب برواية قصة
of these three children,
هؤلاء الثلاث أطفال
Pranitha, Shaheen and Anjali.
برانيثا , و شاهين , و أنجلي
Pranitha's mother was a woman in prostitution,
كانت أم برانيثا تعمل في البغاء
a prostituted person.
فتاة هوى
She got infected with HIV,
أصيبت بفيروس نقص المناعة البشرية HIV
and towards the end of her life,
وعندما شارفت حياتها على الإنتهاء
when she was in the final stages of AIDS,
بعدما وصلت للمرحلة النهائية للإيدز
she could not prostitute,
لم يعد بإمكانها ممارسة البغاء
so she sold four-year-old Pranitha to a broker.
لذا باعت برانيثا ذات الـ4 سنوات إلى سمسار
By the time we got the information, we reached there,
وفي الوقت الذي حصلنا به على المعلومة , وصلنا هناك
Pranitha was already raped by three men.
ووجدنا برانيثا قد إغتصبها 3 رجال
Shaheen's background I don't even know.
لا أعرف عن خلفية شاهين
We found her in a railway track,
ولكننا وجدناها على السكة الحديدية
raped by many, many men, I don't know many.
مغتصبة من عدة رجال , لا أعلم عددهم
But the indications of that on her body was
ولكن مؤشرات الكثرة كانت على جسدها
that her intestine was outside her body.
حيث أن أمعائها خرجت من جسدها
And when we took her to the hospital
وعندما حملناها إلى المستشفى
she needed 32 stitches to put back her intestine into her body.
إحتاجت إلى 32 غرزة لإعادة أمعائها إلى الداخل
We still don't know who her parents are, who she is.
لا نعلم حقًا من هم والديها , ومن كانت هي
All that we know that hundreds of men
جل ما نعرفه أن مئات الرجال
had used her brutally.
إستخدموها بوحشية
Anjali's father, a drunkard,
وأما والد أنجلي فقد كان سكير
sold his child for pornography.
باع طفلته من أجل مواد إباحية
You're seeing here images of
ترون هنا صور لأطفال
three years, four-year-olds, and five-year-old children
في عمر الثالثة , و الرابعة , والخامسة
who have been trafficked for commercial sexual exploitation.
الذين توجر بهم لتجارة الإستغلال الجنسي
In this country, and across the globe,
في هذا البلد , وحول العالم
hundreds and thousands of children,
مئات الأطفال و الآلاف منهم
as young as three, as young as four,
بعمر الثالثة , وبعمر الرابعة
are sold into sexual slavery.
يباعون للعبودية الجنسية
But that's not the only purpose that human beings are sold for.
ولكن هذا ليس السبب الوحيد لبيع البشر
They are sold in the name of adoption.
إنهم يباعون بإسم التبني
They are sold in the name of organ trade.
وتجارة الأعضاء
They are sold in the name of forced labor,
والعمالة القسرية
camel jockeying, anything, everything.
سياسة الجمال ,و أي شيء , و كل شيء
I work on the issue of commercial sexual exploitation.
أعمل في قضايا تجارة الإستغلال الجنسي
And I tell you stories from there.
وسأروي لكم قصص من هناك
My own journey to work with these children
بدأت رحلتي في العمل مع هؤلاء الأطفال
started as a teenager.
عندما كنت مراهقة
I was 15 when I was gang-raped by eight men.
كنت أبلغ من العمر 15 سنة , وقام 8 رجال بإغتصابي جماعيا
I don't remember the rape part of it so much
لا أتذكر كثيرًا عملية إغتصابي
as much as the anger part of it.
بقدر ما أتذكر غضبي
Yes, there were eight men who defiled me, raped me,
نعم ..كانوا 8 رجال دنسوني , وإغتصبوني
but that didn't go into my consciousness.
ولكن لم يتخلل ذلك وعيي
I never felt like a victim, then or now.
لم أشعر قط بأني ضحية حتى اليوم
But what lingered from then till now -- I am 40 today --
ولكن ما بقي بداخلي حتى الآن ( أبلغ الـ40 من عمري اليوم )
is this huge outrageous anger.
هو الغضب العارم بداخلي
Two years, I was ostracized, I was stigmatized, I was isolated,
لعامين نبذت, و وُصمت بالعار , وعزلوني
because I was a victim.
لأني كنت ضحية
And that's what we do to all traffic survivors.
وهذا ما نفعله لكل الذين تم إنقاذهم من التجارة البشرية
We, as a society, we have PhDs
نحن كمجتمع لدينا دكتوراه في
in victimizing a victim.
إشعار الضحية بأنه كذلك
Right from the age of 15,
منذ أن كان عمري 15
when I started looking around me,
عندما بدأت أن أنظر حولي
I started seeing hundreds and thousands of women and children
أصبحت أرى المئات من النساء والأطفال والآلاف منهم
who are left in sexual slavery-like practices,
ممن يتُركون في ممارسات شبيهة للإستعباد الجنسي
but have absolutely no respite,
ولكن ليس لديهم أي فرصة إطلاقًا
because we don't allow them to come in.
لأننا لا نسمح لهم بالمجيء
Where does their journey begin?
أين تبدأ رحلتهم ؟
Most of them come from very optionless families,
يأتي الكثير منهم من عائلات إستثنائية جدا
not just poor.
وليس فقط الأسر الفقيرة
You have even the middle class sometimes getting trafficked.
وكما أن الطبقة الوسطى بها الإتجار بالبشر
I had this I.S. officer's daughter,
كانت لدي قضيه بها إبنة موظف لأمن المعلومات
who is 14 years old, studying in ninth standard,
تبلغ من العمر 14 عامًا , وتدرس بالمرحلة التاسعة ( السنة 3 بالمرحلة المتوسطة)
who was raped chatting with one individual,
التي إغتصبت بسبب دردشتها مع شخص
and ran away from home because she wanted to become a heroine,
وهربت من بيتها لأنها أرادت أن تصبح بطلة سينمائية
who was trafficked.
وإنتهى بها المطاف في التجارة البشرية
I have hundreds and thousands of stories of very very well-to-do families,
لدي مئات القصص و الآلاف منها لأسر بمستويات جيدة , وممتازة جدا
and children from well-to-do families,
وأطفال خضعوا للتجارة البشرية
who are getting trafficked.
وهم أبناء هذه الأسر ذات المستوى الجيد
These people are deceived, forced.
هؤلاء الأطفال قد خدعوا , وأرغموا
99.9 percent of them
إن 99.9% منهم
resist being inducted into prostitution.
رفضوا الدخول في عالم البغاء
Some pay the price for it.
بعضهم يدفع الثمن لذلك
They're killed; we don't even hear about them.
إنهم يُقتلون , ولا نسمع عنهم أي شيء
They are voiceless, [unclear],
إنهم بلا أصوات
nameless people.
بلا أسماء
But the rest, who succumb into it,
ولكن البقية الذين إستسلموا لهم
go through everyday torture.
يخضعون للتعذيب كل يوم
Because the men who come to them are not men who want to make you your girlfriends,
لأن الرجال الذين يأتون إليهم لا يريدون جعلكِ حبيبتهم
or who want to have a family with you.
ولا يريدون تكوين أسرة معكِ
These are men who buy you for an hour, for a day,
هؤلاء الرجال من يبتاعونكِ من أجل ساعة , أو من أجل يوم
and use you, throw you.
ويستخدمونكِ , ثم يرمونكِ
Each of the girls that I have rescued --
كل الفتيات الذين أنقذتهم ...
I have rescued more than 3,200 girls --
( لقد أنقذت 3,200 فتاة )
each of them tell me one story in common ...
كل الفتيات الذين انقذتهم يخبروني بقصة واحدة مشتركة
(Applause)
( تصفيق)
one story about one man, at least,
قصة واحدة بشأن رجل واحد على الأقل ..
putting chili powder in her vagina,
يضع مسحوق الفلفل الأحمر في داخل أعضائها التناسلية
one man taking a cigarette and burning her,
رجل واحد يشعل السيجار ليحرقها به
one man whipping her.
رجل واحد يجلدها بالسوط
We are living among those men: they're our brothers, fathers,
نحن نعيش وسط هؤلاء الرجال : إنهم إخواننا , و آبائنا
uncles, cousins, all around us.
وأعمامنا , وأبناء أعمامنا , هم حولنا
And we are silent about them.
ونحن صامتين بشأنهم
We think it is easy money.
نظن أنه مال سهل المكسب
We think it is shortcut.
نظن أنها طريقة مختصرة
We think the person likes to do what she's doing.
نظن أنها تحب ما تفعله
But the extra bonuses that she gets
بيد أن العلاوات الإضافية التي تحصل عليها
is various infections, sexually transmitted infections,
هي عدوى متنوعة , و أمراض معدية تنتقل بالإتصال الجنسي
HIV, AIDS, syphilis, gonorrhea, you name it,
فيروس نقص المناعة البشرية , و الإيدز , والزهري , والسيلان ..والعديد من الأمراض
substance abuse, drugs, everything under the sun.
إساءه إستخدام المواد المخدرة , والمخدرات , وإساءه إستخدام كل شيء حولك
And one day she gives up on you and me,
وفي يوم من الأيام يقنط إيمانها بك , وبي
because we have no options for her.
لأننا لا نملك أي خيارات لها
And therefore she starts normalizing this exploitation.
ولهذا السبب تبدأ في تطبيع الإستغلال الجنسي
She believes, "Yes, this is it, this is what my destiny is about."
تظن بقولها : "نعم هذا هو الحال , هذا ما آل إليه قدري"
And this is normal, to get raped by 100 men a day.
وأن 100 رجل يغتصبها في اليوم هو أمر طبيعي
And it's abnormal to live in a shelter.
ومن غير الطبيعي أن تعيش في ملجأ
It's abnormal to get rehabilitated.
أو تخضع لإعادة التأهيل
It's in that context that I work.
في ذلك الحال أنا أعمل
It's in that context that I rescue children.
في ذلك الحال أنا أنقذ الأطفال
I've rescued children as young as three years,
لقد أنقذت أطفال بعمر الثلاث سنوات
and I've rescued women as old as 40 years.
وأنقذت نساء بعمر الأربعين سنة
When I rescued them, one of the biggest challenges I had
وعندما أنقذتهن كانت أصعب التحديات التي واجهتها
was where do I begin.
هو من أين أبدأ
Because I had lots of them
لأن الكثير منهن
who were already HIV infected.
كانوا مصابات في ذلك اللحين بفيروس نقص المناعة البشرية
One third of the people I rescue
ثلث الأشخاص الذين أنقذتهم
are HIV positive.
مصابون بفيروس نقص المناعة البشرية
And therefore my challenge was to
ولهذا كان التحدي بالنسبة لي
understand how can I get out
أن أحاول إخراج
the power from this pain.
القوة النابعة من هذا الألم
And for me, I was my greatest experience.
وبالنسبة لي , كنت أنا تجربتي العظيمة
Understanding my own self,
حيث فهمت ذاتي
understanding my own pain,
وأدركت ألمي
my own isolation,
وفي عزلتي
was my greatest teacher.
كانت تكمن معلمتي العظيمة
Because what we did with these girls
لأن ما فعلناه مع هؤلاء الأطفال
is to understand their potential.
هو معرفة إمكانياتهم..
You see a girl here who is trained as a welder.
أترون هذه الفتاة تدربت على اللحامة
She works for a very big company,
وهي تعمل لشركة كبيرة جدًا
a workshop in Hyderabad,
تحديدًا في ورشة عمل في مدينة حيدر آباد
making furnitures.
تصنع الأثاث
She earns around 12,000 rupees.
وتكسب حوالي 12,000 روبية
She is an illiterate girl,
هذه الفتاة الأمية
trained, skilled as a welder.
تدربت , و برعت في اللحامة
Why welding and why not computers?
ولماذا اللحامة وليس مجال الحاسب؟
We felt, one of the things that these girls had
شعرنا بأن إحدى الأشياء لدى هؤلاء الفتيات
is immense amount of courage.
هو الكم الهائل من الشجاعة لديهن
They did not have any pardas inside their body,
لم يكن لديهن أي ستار لأجسامهن
hijabs inside themselves;
ولا غطاء لذاتهن
they've crossed the barrier of it.
لقد تخطين هذه الحواجز النفسية
And therefore they could fight in a male-dominated world,
ولهذا إستطعن الكفاح في عالم الرجل
very easily, and not feel very shy about it.
بكل سهولة , بدون الشعور بالحياء الشديد لذلك
We have trained girls as carpenters,
دربنا فتيات في مجال النجارة
as masons,
ومجال البناء
as security guards, as cab drivers.
والحراسة الأمنية , و قيادة سيارات الأجرة
And each one of them are excelling
وكل واحدة منهن تبرع
in their chosen field,
في المجال الذي اختارته
gaining confidence, restoring dignity,
مما زاد من ثقتهن بنفسهن , ومما جعلهن يستعدن كرامتهن
and building hopes in their own lives.
وتمكنوا من تعزيز الأمل في حياتهن
These girls are also working in big construction companies
هؤلاء الفتيات أيضا يعملن في شركات كبيرة للبناء
like Ram-ki construction, as masons, full-time masons.
مثل شركة (رام-كي) للبناء , و يعملن بنائات بدوام كامل
What has been my challenge?
ماذا كان التحدي بالنسبة لي ؟
My challenge has not been the traffickers who beat me up.
لم يكن التحدي لي تجار البشر الذين كانوا يوسعوني ضربًا
I've been beaten up more than 14 times in my life.
لقد تعرضت للضرب أكثر من 14 مرة في حياتي
I can't hear from my right ear.
لا أستطيع السماع من أذني اليمنى
I've lost a staff of mine who was murdered
قتل أحد العاملين معي
while on a rescue.
في إحدى عمليات الإنقاذ
My biggest challenge
ولكن أكبر تحديٍ
is society.
لي هو المجتمع !
It's you and me.
إنه انت و أنا
My biggest challenge is your blocks to accept these victims
أكبر تحدي لي هو قبول الضحايا في حيك السكني
as our own.
كفرد ينتمي لنا
A very supportive friend of mine,
لدي صديقة تدعمني كثيرًا
a well-wisher of mine,
صديقة تتمنى كل الخير لي
used to give me every month, 2,000 rupees for vegetables.
كانت تعطيني 2000 روبية كل شهر من أجل إبتياع الخضار
When her mother fell sick she said,
عندما مرضت والدتها قالت لي
"Sunitha, you have so much of contacts.
((سونيتا , لديك الكثير من المعارف
Can you get somebody in my house to work,
هل بإمكانك إحضار شخص إلى بيتي للعمل
so that she can look after my mother?"
حتى تعتني بوالدتي؟))
And there is a long pause.
وكانت هناك وقفة زمنية طويلة
And then she says, "Not one of our girls."
وبعدها قالت " لكن ليست واحدة من فتياتنا"
It's very fashionable to talk about human trafficking,
من الراقي جدًا الحديث عن تجارة البشر
in this fantastic A-C hall.
في القاعات المكيفة
It's very nice for discussion, discourse,
ومن الجميل جدًا إستخدام الموضوع في النقاش , والمحاضرة عنه
making films and everything.
إنتاج الأفلام عنه , وكل شيء
But it is not nice to bring them to our homes.
ولكن ليس جميلًا إحضارهم إلى بيوتنا
It's not nice to give them employment in our factories, our companies.
و ليس جميًلا أن نعطيهم وظائف في مصانعنا , أو شركاتنا
It's not nice for our children to study with their children.
وليس جميًلا أن يدرس أبنائنا بجانب أبنائهم
There it ends.
في تلك اللحظة ينتهي كل شيء
That's my biggest challenge.
هذا أكبر تحدي لي
If I'm here today, I'm here not only as Sunitha Krishnan.
إذا كنت هنا اليوم , فأنا لست هنا لأني (سونيتا كريشنان)
I'm here as a voice of the victims and survivors of human trafficking.
بل أنا هنا كـصوت لضحايا التجارة البشرية والناجين منها
They need your compassion.
يحتاجون عطفكم
They need your empathy.
يحتاجون تعاطفكم
They need, much more than anything else,
وأكثر شيء يحتاجونه منكم
your acceptance.
هو قبولكم ..
Many times when I talk to people,
في الكثير من المرات التي أتحدث بها إلى الناس
I keep telling them one thing:
أقول لهم على الدوام , شيئا واحدًا
don't tell me hundred ways
( لا تخبروني بمئات الطرق
how you cannot respond to this problem.
التي لا تمكنكم من التجاوب مع المشكلة
Can you ply your mind for that one way
عوضا عن ذلك هلا إستعملتم عقلكم لإيجاد طريقة واحدة
that you can respond to the problem?
بها تستطيعون التجاوب مع المشكلة؟ )
And that's what I'm here for,
ولهذا أنا هنا اليوم
asking for your support,
أسألكم الدعم
demanding for your support,
وأطالب به
requesting for your support.
وألتمسه منكم
Can you break your culture of silence?
هلا كسرتم ثقافة الصمت؟
Can you speak to at least two persons about this story?
هلا أخبرتم شخصين على الأقل عن هذه القصة؟
Tell them this story. Convince them to tell the story to another two persons.
قل لهم هذه القصة , وأقنعهم بإخبار القصة لشخصين آخرين
I'm not asking you all to become Mahatma Gandhis
انا لا أطلب منكم أن تصبحوا (المهاتما غاندي)
or Martin Luther Kings, or Medha Patkars,
او (مارتن لوثر كينغ) , أو (مدحة باتكرز)
or something like that.
او أي احد مثلهم
I'm asking you, in your limited world,
أنا أطلب منكم في عالمكم المحدود
can you open your minds? Can you open your hearts?
هلا فتحتم عقلكم ؟ هلا فتحتم قلبكم ؟
Can you just encompass these people too?
هل تستطيعون شمل هؤلاء الأشخاص أيضا؟
Because they are also a part of us.
لأنهم أيضا جزء منا
They are also part of this world.
وجزء من العالم
I'm asking you, for these children,
أطلب منكم لأجل هؤلاء الأطفال
whose faces you see, they're no more.
الذين ترون وجوههم , لكنهم ليسوا أحياء
They died of AIDS last year.
لقد ماتوا السنة الماضية على إثر الإيدز
I'm asking you to help them,
أطلب منكم مساعدتكم
accept as human beings --
وقبولهم كـ بشر
not as philanthropy, not as charity,
وليس كعمل خيري , أو على سبيل الصدقة
but as human beings who deserve all our support.
ولكن كبشر يستحقون كل دعمكم
I'm asking you this because no child, no human being,
أطلب منكم ذلك لأنه لايوجد أي طفل , أو إنسان
deserves what these children have gone through.
يستحق ما جرى لهؤلاء الأطفال
Thank you.
شكرا لكم ..
(Applause)
(تصفيق)